[Music]
[âm nhạc]
[Applause]
[Vỗ tay]
Tran Nhan Tong,
Trần Nhân Tông
Dharma speaker,
pháp loa
Huyen Quang
Huyền Quang
Tue Bich, composed the story of the Zen ascetic
Tuệ Bích phổ ra
singer, the founder of the
nỗi dòng thiền đầu đà ca sĩ
sacred ancestral land of
đất tổ linh thiêng
Uong Bi,
Uông Bí
Quang Ninh,
Quảng Ninh
continuing the Zen singer lineage.
nối dõi dòng thiền
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Quang Tue Bich district, composed the story of Hanh,
huyện Quang Tuệ Bích phổ ra chuyện Hanh
Dau Da, Dau Da, and lettuce, the founder of the sacred ancestral land of Yen Thanh,
đậu đà đậu đà cà diếp tổ sư đất tổ linh
becoming bitter, Uong Bi, Quang Ninh,
thiêng Yên trở thành đắng Uông Bí Quảng
the land of spiritual mushrooms.
Ninh đất thổ linh chi
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Vietnam, Buddha, Tran Nhan Tong,
Việt Nam Phật Tổ Trần Nhân Tông
for the sake of King Anh Minh,
vì vua anh Minh
in the righteous Dharma of Buddha, ruled the country, brought peace to the people, suppressed
nơi chính pháp phật đà trị Quốc An dân
rebellions and invasions, kept the borders safe. The throne
Dẹp Loạn xâm lăng giữ yên bờ cõi Ngai
appeared,
Vàng hiện Duy
only he left the imperial city, hid his name in
mình chỉ thiên hạ rời bỏ hoàng thành ẩn
Yen Tu mountain, attained
danh núi Yên Tử đầu đã An tu đắc thành
enlightenment, continued the Zen lineage, continued the
đạo quả nối dõi dòng thiền nối dõi dòng
Zen master lineage of Chu, for a thousand
thiền sư tổ Chu cứ
years. A thousand years in Africa, the ancestral land of Uong
ngàn năm Ngàn năm Châu Phi đất tổ Uống
Bi, Quang Ninh, the origin of human life, Buddhist
Bí Quảng Ninh nguồn gốc nhân sinh Phật
Dharma flourishing, continuing the Zen lineage of the
pháp Thịnh Hưng nối dõi dòng thiền đất
sacred ancestral land of Uong Bi,
tổ linh thiêng
Quang Ninh, composed the story of Hanh, Dau Da, Dau Da, and lettuce, the
huyện Quang Tuệ Bích phổ ra trên hành
founder of the sacred ancestral land of
đậu đà đậu đà cà diếp tổ sư đất tổ linh
Yen Tu, becoming Uong Bi,
thiêng Yên Tử Thành đáng Uông Bí Quảng
Quang Ninh, the sacred ancestral land of Dharma speaker.
pháp Loan huyện Quang Tuệ Bích phổ ra
Continuing the lineage of the Zen ascetic Ca Diep, the founder of the
nối dòng thiền đầu đà Cá diếp tổ sư đất
sacred ancestral land of Uong Bi, Quang Ninh. The Dharma practice
tổ linh thiêng Uống Bí Quảng Ninh Pháp
begins in the sacred land of Yen Tu, Thanh
hành đầu ra đất to linh thiêng Yên Tử
Dang, Uong Bi, Quang Ninh. Lying about the Zen
Thành Đặng Uông Bí Quảng Ninh nói dối
lineage of Ca Diep, the founder of the
dòng thiền Ca Diếp tổ sư đất tổ linh
sacred ancestral land, continuing the Zen lineage.
thiêng nối dõi dòng thiền
Singer
ca sĩ
[Music] [Music] [
[âm nhạc]